大家好
JEFF: Hello.
谢谢
Thank you.
在开始前  我想先做点小事儿
Before we get started, I actually need to go over something.
这些是我的孩子们
These are my boys.
等我从这个会场回家之后  我要做的第一件事就是
The first thing I do when I come home from a conference is show
把我的这段演讲视频给他们看
them the video of my talk.
所以  请在场的各位配合我一下
So, what I would like for everyone here to do, if you could,
我假装再次来到讲台  而你们则尽可能大声的欢迎我  这样一来
is me to pretend to come on stage and you cheer as loudly as you can, so, when
当我回到家的时候  他们就会觉得每个人都很喜欢他老爹我
I come home, they think everyone loves their daddy.
我马上就要翻到幻灯片首页  然后跑上讲台
I'm going to run up on the title slide, and run up on to the stage.
能多大声就多大声（的欢迎我）就最好了
As loud as you can will be great.
谢谢
Thank you!
请坐
[CHEERING] . JEFF: Sit down!
Sit down!
我有很多要讲的
I've got a lot to go over.
非常感谢
Thank you so much.
能来这里真是太好了
It's great to be here.
朋友们  别这样  我这次要讲的很多
Guys, come on, I've got a lot to cover!
我是 Jeff Cross  我是 Angular 移动技术组的 Tech lead  和标题上说的一样
So, I'm Jeff Cross, the tech lead of the mobile team on Angular, and as the title says,
我大概是这次大会中最值得信任的人了
I'm probably the most trustworthy person here at the conference.
如果你这次只打算听一个演讲  那就是这个了
If you're going to one talk the whole time, this is
这可能是最好的演讲了
probably the best one to be at!
今天你实际上能用一场演讲的钱听两场
You actually get two talks for the price of one today,
因为我的同事 Alex Rickabaugh 将会在我的演讲结束之后再讲一场
because my colleague, Alex Rickabaugh, is going to give a talk right after mine.
Alex 和我就像是超级男孩乐队  我们一起合作
Alex and me are like the band Nsync where we collaborate
一起出专辑  但有时我们也独自做
together and make albums together, but once in a while, we make solo
项目
projects.
（在这个比喻中）  我就是 Justin Timberlake （超级男孩乐队的队长）
I'm Justin Timberlake.
我们一回去就努力工作  让移动应用更加牛逼
We will be getting back to work to make mobile awesome.
我这次的目标就是传授你一些知识  让你自己决定你的移动应用该选用
My goal is to equip you with the knowledge so that you can decide a mobile
何种策略   这就像挑选工具  比如选取工具和策略
strategy for your applications, like clicking the tools - picking the tools and strategies
为正式的应用而不是为自家的玩具应用
to use for serious applications, not the toy apps you build at home.
Alex 会讲述如何充分发挥你的移动
Alex is going to talk about making the most of your mobile
Web 开发经验
web experience.
我一共有 20 分钟
I've got 20 minutes.
我们要怎样在这 20 分钟讲述这么多内容呢？
What can we fit in 20 minutes?
我想我们可以评估并比较每一个工具、库以及
I think we can evaluate and compare every tool, library and
移动开发方面的理念  或者  实际一点  我们可以聚焦于和Angular有关的那些细节
idea in the mobile landscape, or, maybe to be practical, we can focus on the pieces that
也就是点评Angular所集成的具体工具
pertain to Angular, so - Angular looking at tools that are specifically integrated with
我将会讲的很快  我将会
- I'm going to be talking fast, I'm going to
分享这些幻灯片  它们当中包含了很多信息
share the slides, they've got lots of information inside.
即使你错过了  以后也能靠它们追上来
If you get lost, you'll catch up later.
我们先来看看一些移动技术爱好者  他们天天讨论他们的
Let's take a look at some of the mobile enthusiasts who go on and on about their
工具  远远超过了我们想听的极限
tools way longer than any of us care to hear about them.
公平起见  我们先从 Angular 移动技术组开始
To be fair, we will start with the Angular Mobile Team.
>> 对渐进式 Web 应用  我们讨论的很多
>> We talk a lot about progressive web apps.
我们在构建这些渐进式 Web 应用方面投入了很多时间
It's where we spend a lot of our time is building these progressive web apps.
这种思路可以让构建出的 Web 应用具有与
It's just a way of thinking about building web apps
原生应用相似的操作感和行为
to feel like installed native applications to have the same kind of feel and behaviour,
可以安装到首屏  可以离线工作  可以立即工作  等等
installing the home screen, working offline, working instantly, those kind of things.
对渐进式 Web 应用  我们谈论了那么多  但问题在于
So we talk a lot about it, and the question is
在目前的技术条件下  它是现实的应用构建方案吗？
it the one true way to build applications today?
你能放下构建应用时所考虑的一切吗？
Can you drop everything you thought about building applications?
能单独构建渐进式 Web 应用吗？
Can just build progressive web apps?
我们稍后再探讨它
We will look into that later.
首先  我们看看另一些爱好者
First, let's look at some other enthusiasts.
[Audio played].
Adam 是一个 Ionic 开发者
Adam is a developer on Ionic as you can from the five
你从他五次谈到 Ionic 就能看出来
times he said it.
也许每个人都听说过 Ionic
Everyone has heard of Ionic, probably.
它是构建于 Cordova 之上的一个混合式（Hybrid）应用方案
It's a cool hybrid thing built on Cordoba.
你可以把它们装在手机上  为其添加原生特性  这样一来  它既有
You can put them on phones, add native features, while having a nice
良好的用户体验又能与 Web 应用分享代码以及复用你的 Web 开发技能
experience and sharing code with web apps and using your web app skills.
所以我们有渐进式Web应用
We've got progressive web apps.
还有什么别的方式？
What else do we have?
[Audio played].
还有一个产品  名叫 Native Script
So there is a product called native script.
如你所见
As you saw there.
Jen Looper 将会演讲  还有 Ionic 的 Adam 和 Brandy 也将随后演讲  你们绝对应该去听听他们的演讲 NativeScript 是另一种截然不同的方式
Luke Luke Luke will be native script is a kind of different approach.
和 Cordova 不同  这并不是 Hybrid 技术  不过你照样可以写
It's not hybrid in the same sense as Cordova but you to get to write
JavaScript 和 TypeScript 它在运行时也像个应用程序，但它的UI是原生的
JavaScript and TypeScript and it runs at the same time as the application but you have
具备硬件访问能力  平滑的滚屏  以及大量缓动效果等
native UI, with hardware acceleration, nice smooth scrolling, all that with a lot of ease.
所以  我们有了三个相互竞争的候选技术
So we've got these three contenders.
嗯  你知道吗？
And, you know what?
在特定的场景中并不一定要使用单一的策略
No single strategy has to be used in isolation.
可能多数情况下会使用它们的某种组合  可能是 Web 和 NativeScript
Probably most will be combined with something else, maybe web
也可能是 Web 和 Ionic
and NativeScript, maybe web and Ionic.
我们要看看它们如何互补的
We want to look at how they complement each other, what are the strengths and advantages
看看你所做的选择  其强项和优点何在
are the different choices you might make?
所以  我们今天要问的问题是  我们需要一个 Web 应用吗？
So the questions we want to answer today are: do I need a web app?
也就是说  我们要构建一个
Is it strategically sound to have it built as a
没有原生组件的 Web 应用吗？
web app with no native component?
如果理由不充分或不必要  那么我们是该用 Hybrid 还是 Native
If it is not sufficient or necessary, should I use hybrid
还是类似的工具？
or native JavaScript or some tools like them?
我们来看看Angular世界的Mobile发展方向
Let's look and the South of mobile in Angular land.
我把这些分为四类：分发 —— 用户如何拿到你的应用；
I've got four categories I've broken this down to: distribution, how users
能力 —— 有哪些API？在各种不同的方式下，你能或不能做到什么？
get a hold of your app; capabilities - what are the APIs, the things you can and can't
do with different approaches?
性能 —— 在各种不同的方式下，性能的特征是怎样的？
Performance, what are the performance characteristics of
different approaches?
生产率 —— 在使用不同工具时  你团队的开发效率如何？
Productivity: how effective is your team going to be with different
tools?
先从分发开始讲起  用户要如何获得你的应用？
Starting with distribution, how do users get your app?
可搜索性是一个很重要的因素
Searchability is a big factor here.
用户如何通过搜索引擎或应用商店找到该应用？
How do they find it in search engines and app stores?
可分享性  如何通过你的应用分享内容  或者
Share-ability, how does content from your app get shared or
如何分享你的应用本身？
how does your app itself get shared?
首次使用时的体验
The first-use experience.
当用户听说了你的应用时  就会通过搜索引擎或其它什么地方来查找它
When a user hears about your app, finds it in a search engine,
用户容易找到它吗？以及  你的应用该如何升级？
finds it somewhere else, how easily can they use it, and how does the updating of
your app occur?
要想获得可搜索性  用户该如何通过搜索引擎来发现这些内容？
Getting into searchability, how do users discover the content via search
engines?
有趣的是：Alex和我所属的公司被称为Google，而这个公司
There is an interesting fact: the company Alex and I work for is called
在1997年就已经存在了  在那里你可以在输入框中输入任何想找东西
Google, and we have had this website since about 1997 where you can type in anything
然后Google就会试图在整个互联网上找到
you want in a text field and it will look around the whole internet and try to find
你想要的内容
content that matches what you want.
我们提供一些广告  而当用户点击广告这些时
We have ads on it, and, when people click those
我们就能因此而赚到钱
ads, we get money for it.
这也是我们资助Angular开发的方式
This is how we fund Angular development.
Angular看起来像个伟大的项目  但是我们要
Angular seems like this great project but we have to make
以某种方式赚到钱  我们的做法就是这样的
make money somehow and that's how we do.
这也是人们查找应用、内容、新文章等等的主流方式
It's a big way that people find apps, content, news articles, whatever, and they've
他们通过抓取网站而获益  而最近几年则通过抓取JavaScript应用而获益
gotten pretty good at crawling websites and in the last few years got good at crawling
JavaScript apps.
他们可以渲染它、抓取它并为它建立索引
They can render it, crawl it, index it.
但是你的网站可能因为某种原因而难以被爬虫索引到
But even if your site for whatever reason has a hard time being
还有些搜索引擎不支持这种高级抓取方式
crawler-indexed, or some search engines just don't have advanced crawling, now with
现在  借助 Universal  Angular 2 具备了预先渲染（Prerender）的能力
Angular 2 there is a capability of pre-rendering using Universal.
对于 Web 应用来说  可以轻松获得搜索引擎优化带来的优点
The web apps are the most easy experience that take advantage of
search engine optimisation.
借助 Universal 你可以弥补
With universal, you eliminate the downsides before
在搜索引擎优化（SEO）方面的缺点
you have search-engine optimisation.
Hybrid 和 Native 应用中的内容都可以被 Google 搜索到
Hybrid and native app content can appear in Google search.
你可以给 Google 一些提示来告诉它如何链接到你的内容
You can give Google hints about links to your content, and they can
然后它就可以在你的 Android 原生应用中打开并在 WebView 中显示这些内容
open it in your native app and show it in the
web view on your Android phone.
问题在于  它只能由支持 URL 的 Web 应用来使用
But the thing is, it has to be backed by a web app with URL.
所以  你要把内容中的各个部分都告诉 Google “这块儿内容在我的原生应用中”
So any piece of content that you have that you tell Google, "This piece of
所以你不得不为它在 Web 上提供一个后备网址（fallback URL）
content is my native app", you have to have a fallback URL to go to on the web.
这也就是我们即将谈论的主要方案之一
That's a big theme of the themes we are going to talk about.
指向原生应用的URL是进行索引和分享内容的关键所在
URL with a native app are a key component to index and share content.
通过 Web 搜索不是唯一的途径
Web search isn't the only game in town.
手机操作系统提供了操作层面的搜索功能
Mobile operating systems provide operating-level
在那里  你可以搜索设备上或 Web 上的内容  并且提供了应用商店的搜索功能
system search where you can search content on your device or on the web, and to provide
app store search.
而 Web 应用无法出现在对应用商店的搜索中
With web apps, you cannot appear in app store search.
但如果你有一个渐进式 Web 应用 你就能把它安装在手机的首屏
If I have a progressive web app, maybe installed on
而 iPhone 和 Android 的应用商店中无论何时都不会出现它们
my home screen and all that, and the iPhone and Android app store don't show those
apps for whatever reasons.
不过  公开的 Web 应用的内容也可以出现在你的原生操作系统搜索中
Public web app content may appear in your native operating
system search, though.
我可以在自己的设备上搜索 AngularJS 而下方的播客列表中会描述内容的来源
I can search for my device, Angular JS, podcasts below that it
describes content from.
所以  你可能想要在原生JavaScript应用中嵌入Hybrid内容 比如
So, you might need a hybrid for a native JavaScript app if your
用户期待在应用商店的搜索中看到这些内容  或者  他们希望使用原生的搜索功能找到你应用中的私有内容
users expect to see you in the app store search or if they want to see your app's private
content using native search.
如果有一个 Web 应用  你的公开内容就能显示在
If you have a web app, your content can show up in a
原生搜索中  但是只有当你安装了一个原生应用时，才能看到你的私有内容
native search but your private content can only show up if you're installed in a native
app.
总而言之  可搜索性就是  如果你的应用及其内容应该被主流搜索引擎发现
In summary of searchability, if your app and its content should be discovered in
它就必须支持 Web 爬虫选项
major search engines, there must be a crawler web option.
如果它要出现在应用商店中，它就必须有一个原生版本的应用
If it is in app stores, there must be a native version of the app.
如果私有内容需要能在操作系统层面被发现
If the private content is discoverable by operating-level system search, there must
它就必须被安装成一个原生或Hybrid版本的应用
be a native or hybrid version of the app installed.
可分享性：用户要分享你的内容有多容易？
Shareability: how easily do users share your content?
我们先让 Web 支持它
Let's apply this to web first.
如果我要分享照片、内容或别的什么
If I want to share a photo, content, anything,
那就需要开发者给用户指出该如何以及在哪里分享它
it is up to me as a developer to figure out how and where the user can share that.
很多时候  如果想要从设备上获取照片
A lot of times, if I want to get a photo from the
我就要得到一个输入文件  而用户则不得不从文件系统中去选取照片
device, I will have a file input, and they'll have to select a photo from the file system.
这就是因为没有集成原生的gallery（画廊）API或其它API导致的
There's no integration with the native gallery or other APIs.
目前  我没有办法让用户做到：我有内容、然后通过原生的分享机制取到它
There is no way for me to say I have the content, now, what the operating
再分享到任何地方
native sharing mechanism take over and share it to wherever they have, it is
我们只能使用 Web API  所以这个过程不太顺畅 —— 要使用Twilio发送一个文本消息
up to me to work directly with web APIs, so send a text message with Twilio, it is a little
为此  用户还要提供一些认证信息
bit more friction, the user has to provide some authentication for those kind of things,
这种体验可不怎么好
so it is not a nice experience.
这个问题正在得到解决
This is being worked on.
Chrome 开发组的某些人正在制定从 Web 应用中
Someone on the Chrome team is working on speccing, being able to share
分享的规范
from a web app.
处理各种文档的应用可以遵循此规范
Apps that handle that kind of document can take it.
另一种实现方式是让开发人员选择如何分享以及
Another way to put is it is the developer chooses how and
分享到哪里  但对于原生内容  则只有那些安装了相关应用的用户
where they can share, and whereas on Native, it's up to the user to install apps
才能处理这些分享内容
that can handle sharing content.
而问题的另一面在于 Web 应用能处理来自
So, the other side of it is can a web app handle the shares
其它应用的分享吗？
that come from other apps?
目前还没有任何方式能做到
There is no way to do that right now.
如果我要从我的图库应用中分享点什么
If I want to share something from my photo app there's no
那么对于 Web 应用来说  没办法显示在底部  因此也就没办法选择
way for a just a web app to show up in the bottom part, the part where I select where
并分享它
to share it to.
还有一些其它的办法为该应用填补这些缺点
But that is also being worked on as part of the complement to the same
只要把该应用注册成分享器就行了。
app I'm talking about where apps with be registered to add sharing intense.
我们来看看其它方面，并审视下Hybrid应用和
Let's take a look at the other side and look at hybrid
原生JavaScript应用
and native JavaScript apps.
你得到了 Web 所擅长的可伸缩性  也能做到 Web 所能做的一切
You've got the flexibility of the web, you can do everything
但同时你还有原生操作系统的支持  于是你还可以选择
you can do with web, but you have the native operating system support, so you can
推迟提供这种操作方式  而用另一种方式达到分享这些内容的目的
defer to what the operating provides, in terms of share targets for content.
Ionic的插件和NativeScript能让你
And plugins for Ionic, and NativeScript make this
轻松实现分享  只需要通过少量配置  付出很小的努力就能实现
easy to share with little effort and little configuration.
它们还能处理来自其它应用的分享
They can also handle shares from other applications.
你只要声明了自己的应用能处理分享内容
You can declare your app is able to share content, and they can
他们就能分享给你的应用  而你可以用任何自己喜欢的方式处理它
share your app and you can handle it however you like.
总结一下  Web 应用目前受限于通过 Web API进行分享
To summarise, web app is currently limited to sharing with web APIs,
而且你没办法处理来自其它应用的分享内容  而原生应用可以整合到操作系统级的分享机制中
and you can't handle shares from other applications, and native can handle OS-level
share integration.
如果该功能对你很重要  那么你就需要往自己的实现策略中添加
If that is important to you, then you will need some kind of a native
某种原生成分
component to your strategy.
首次使用时的可体验性
First-use experience-ability.
用户是如何得到你的应用和内容的？
How does the user get your app and content?
显然  用户能越快开始使用你的应用  这种体验就越好
The faster the user can start using your app, the better.
谁有问题没？
I don't know if anyone address with that?
好  继续
Okay.
如果  点击搜索引擎返回的一条结果  并且立刻看到了餐馆的评价
So, clicking a search engine result and immediately seeing a restaurant review is
肯定会比先点击一个链接  然后再安装一个应用  才能看到评价要好一些
better than clicking a link and then installing an app to see a review.
后面这些步骤简直是反人类
It is a dig on Yelp.
我不知道会不会有人喜欢这样
I don't know if they are popular here.
他们总是在一个劲的劝我安装原生应用
They are always nudging me to install the native application.
我不得不跳过其它事情  先安装上这个原生应用
I have to scroll through things to get through the native web app.
“安装”这个需求在用户想使用你的应用时凭空增加了很大的阻力
Installation requirements adds friction to the process of users using your app.
这些阻力导致了中途放弃  而
Friction turns out to be abandonment, and the abandonment
中途放弃总是很糟糕的
is usually pretty bad.
比如这个例子
For this example, actually, with the -- for this example,
Google+的手机应用  当用户拥有这个应用时  他们能显示并点击链接
the Google Plus app, when they have this mobile app that people would show up
当显示在屏幕上时  你和分享的内容之间隔着一大堆事情
to and click links, they had a giant thing that showed up on the screen between you and
他们给了你一个链接好让你去访问一个移动站点  但是就因为这个页面的存在
the content, and they have a link where you can visit the mobile site, but they
有69%的用户中途放弃了！
had a 69% abandonment rate with this page just by having this here.
或许  你可能觉得中途放弃也无所谓
Abandonment might not matter to your app.
用户流失也无所谓
People leaving might not matter.
还有一些合理的情况  你也无所谓
There are some legitimate cases where you may not care.
如果你的原生应用不得不是原生的  你甚至不会从 Web 上的体验方面受到阻碍
Like if your native app is you have to be native, you can't even get a fraction of the
那么需要安装可能也不是坏事  或者可能你只需要面对
experience on web, then maybe installation isn't such a bad things, or maybe you've
少量内部用户  他们可以安装一次然后使用好几年
got a small internal app user base, something they will install once and use for years.
如果在一个每天处理大量快速信息交流的新闻站或点评站上
You don't care about the installation friction so much as a news site or a review site
你可能也不用在乎安装带来的这些阻碍
where you're handling lots of traffic every day for people wanting quick information.
所以  决定是否需要安装  需要经过深思熟虑
So the force to pressure installation needs strong consideration.
你应该已经思考过这个问题了吧
You should really give some thought to this.
要考虑它如何冲击我们的底线  并且看看你是否能
Think about how it impacts your bottom line and figure out if you
轻松的通过移动应用提供更多价值  能否
can ease that a little bit better, provide for value in your mobile app, ease the amount
让你轻松给用户大量的暗示
of hints you give to them.
Android引入了一些有趣的东西  称为Android原生应用
Android's introduced something interesting called Android
通过它  用户可以直接从 Web 访问你的应用而不必先安装它
native apps, where you can access from the web without installing your app yet.
这会鼓励用户稍后安装此应用
It may encourage the user to install the app after
这很棒  稍后我们在讲Ionic和NativeScript时会看到
that point, and this is exciting, and I would like to see more integration of this with
更多的集成方式
Ionic and NativeScript.
和你的用户在一起
Be where your users are.
移除用户和内容之间的障碍
Remove the obstacles between users and their content.
尽可能主动出击  并且通过优雅的提示
Get out of the way as much as you can, and give tasteful hints to
让用户了解到你这个可安装的应用
let users know about your installable apps.
渐进式应用（PWA）就是一个很好的例子
Progressive web apps are a good examples of this.
在用户使用了它们一会儿之后  它们将在屏幕上给出一个提示
After the user has been using them for a while, they will give a hint on the
“看来你喜欢这个应用
screen saying, "You maybe like this app.
你可以把它安装到首屏”
You may want to install it to your home screen."
它不是原生应用  从那一刻开始  用户不用打开浏览器
It is not a native app but they can watch it
就能看到它
from that point but not turned on.
最后一部分我们讲下分发：可升级性 —— 你如何把应用给到用户？
The last part of distribution: update-ability - how do you get the apps to your users?
这是用户体验中最关键的部分
This is pretty critical to user experience.
如果你的升级过程 —— 如果在你添加新特性或者修改原有的东西之后很久用户才能拿到
If your update process - if the time between you adding features or fixing things is delayed
那他们就没法快速访问到这些特性  或是
getting to users, then they don't get access on their features quickly enough, or
那些安全补丁  那些关键的性能提升等等  所以  要作出决策就要考虑好
security fixes, or critical performance improvements, so choosing your strategy based
你该怎么做才能弥补这段时间的损失
on how you can do this is worth some time.
所以  在 Web 上  标准的流程是你作为开发人员把某些东西上传到服务器上
So, on the web, the standard process is you upload something as a developer to
而用户只需要刷新一下  就能得到这些
your server, and the user just refreshes, and they've got it.
这样不错
That's not bad.
用户在加载完所有东西之后才能开始工作  即使是有service-worker（译注：appcache升级版）的支持也一样
They get it after everything loads, but even with service-worker
这个过程中你可以做一些更好看的加载动画和背景
now, you can do more advanced loading and the background.
服务器会告诉你：我现在有一些更新  并且把它们推送给service-worker。
The server can say I've got updates, will push them down
service-worker.
于是  当用户下次打开此应用时  你就能重新加载带有这些新内容的应用
So the next time the user opens the app, you can reload the app with
而不用再通过网络获取  这样你就获得了一些类似原生应用的体验
all the new content without having to fetch anything over the network, so you get kind
而用户也获得了最新的内容、最新的补丁、最新的特性
of a native-like experience with that, but you're still getting fresh content and fresh
fixes, and features for the user.
接下来  我们看看Hybrid应用和原生应用  看看它们如何升级
So let's look at hybrid and native just, how their update
process works.
如果你对应用中的二进制特性或原生特性做出了任何修改
If you change anything with your apps in binary, or any native features,
你都不得不到应用商店中重新发布
you have to republish to app stores.
在iOS上，你要发布就必须通过它的审核和复审
This can halt the process because, with ios, you've
而这会让你不得不暂停这个更新过程
got to go - with with iOS, you've got to go through approval and review.
即使你能让用户自己手动升级  也仍然不得不
Even with manual, you've got to get - you may have to
等待用户
wait for the user.
他们可能都不知道如何手动升级
They may not know they need to update the app manually.
对于Hybrid应用  在原生特性或嵌入式内容变化时
In hybrid apps, they need to be republished if the
才需要重新发布
native features have changed or embedded content has changed.
Hybrid应用的优点是你可以有一大堆内容是
It's an advantage with hybrid apps that you can have a lot of
远程加载到WebView中的  所以  如果你能做到修改这些内容
your content just be remotely loaded in web views, so, if you can change that con tent
—— 任何你想修改的内容 —— 而发布到设备中的部分没变
- you can change that content as much as you want, and what ships in the device is
没有添加新的原生插件  或者  修改已经加载到设备上的皮肤
not changing, not adding new native plugins or changing the skin loaded on the device,
那么你就不用通过应用商店发布  除非你添加了原生特性  而且
then you don't have to push to the app stores until you add native features, and
我还知道即使在这种场合下 NativeScript 也仍然可以修改而不用重新在应用商店发布
I know NativeScript is working update-ability to do that as well.
总之：Web 技术提供了一种路径  Hybrid 和原生 JavaScript 技术解决了由于
Summary: Web provides a path - hybrid and native JavaScript have
应用商店审核而导致的漫长发布周期
potentially longer turnaround because of app store review.
推迟自动更新可能需要经过用户的确认
Delays in automatic updating had potential need for user approval.
好  发布部分我们讲完了  接下来我们讲下一节
So, having covered the distribution, we enough move on to the next major section which
能力
is capabilities.
这一节我们会讲解那些对 原生 或 Web 可用的 API
What I'm going to cover here are APIs that are available in
并且看看我们在各种场合下所能做的有什么差别
native or web, and kind of looking at the discrepancies between what you can do in what
places.
我们来看看用原生你能做到什么  或者  用 Web 你不能做到什么
I'm looking at it as binary that you can or can't do things on the web but
但这些差异都很细微  我鼓励你们自己去评测你们关心的那些 API
it is actually more nuanced than that, and, I encourage you to look some more if there
这些 API 可能在原生下更好  可能在 Hybrid 中的 Web部分更好
are APIs that you care about, which may be much better on native, much better on the
或者原生应用能访问而其它的都不行
web in hybrid and native apps have access that others don't yet.
有些可能只在某些浏览器的试验性分支上才能工作
These may be worked on and are in experimental branches of browsers.
我们来看看这些 API  准备基于 Chrome 和 Safari 来讨论
Let's look at APIs of note, going to talk about Chrome, and Safari.
你可能知道 —— iOS 上的 Chrome 受限于 Safari 因为 Chrome 使用
If you're familiar with - Chrome is limited by Safari because Chrome uses a web
操作系统提供的 WebView  它和 Safari 所用的差不多
view that the operating system provides which is the same is it Safari more or less.
我们从九个方面进行深入剖析
I've got the nine categories we will dive into.
先从原生的行为开始
Starting with native behaviours.
稍后再来看这些幻灯片  因为这里我不会详细讲解它们
Look at these later on the slides because I won't review
them in detail.
我收到通知了吗？
Do I get notifications?
我能在前台看到这些通知吗？
Can I know if I'm in the foreground?
我能设置这些应用的发通知权限吗？
Can I set permissions for the app?
简短来说  对于 iOS Web  还没有办法推送通知
The short story of this is for iOS web, there is no push notifications
而且也没有任何准备开放此功能的迹象
yet and there's no indication when there will be.
这取决于他们啥时候开始实现 service worker 规范
This depends on them implementing service worker to the spec, which
一旦他们开始实现  那可能离开放此功能就不远了  但是迄今为止
there are some indications they have started but they haven't publicly stated that they
他们还没有任何开始实现 service worker 的迹象
have started on implementing service-worker.
接下来你是不是开始关心和周边环境的交互了？
Then you've got surroundings like how can I interact with the world around me?
蓝牙和NFC（近场通讯）
Bluetooth and NFC.
简短地说  Chrome 即将支持蓝牙
The short story is Bluetooth and Chrome is coming soon.
在这个大会上可能会有关于它的演讲  但我不太确定
This may be spoke about at the conference, I'm not sure.
但是 iOS 尚未对此有任何规划  因此目前这还是 Chrome 的独家
But iOS doesn't have any web time line, so this is specced.
Chrome 有这个试验性功能  你今天就可以亲自玩玩看
Chrome has as an experiment, and you can play with that today.
其它的设备特性  比如了解网络信息、电池状态、是否在线、
Then device features like knowing the network info, battery state, am I online?
控制手机的震动马达
Being able to control the vibration motor.
简短地说：电池和网络在 iOS Web 上是不支持的
Short story is: battery network are not availability on iOS web.
看出规律了吧！
Are you seeing a pattern!
只有 Android 和 Chrome 支持
Android and Chrome.
值得注意的是  在Android下的大多数其它浏览器
And also worth noting, most other browsers on Android
也同样在引领潮流
tend to be ahead of the game, too.
比如他们已经支持了 Service Worker 、推送通知
Like they have support for Service Workers, push
以及安装到首屏  所以你就明白我们为何专注于 Chrome 了
notifications, and install a home screen, so you know I'm focusing on Chrome in these.
用户获得了天衣无缝的体验  比如我打开此应用是多么容易啊  这看起来很像原生应用  是不是？
Getting to seamless experience like how easily do I open the app, does it feel like
native?
它能开启离线模式
Does it have an offline mode?
还有安装到首屏功能  这样我就能
Having home screen installation, so I can launch
从首屏启动了  还能在背后默默地同步内容
from the home screen, being able to sync things in the background, being able to
还能与其它应用通讯
communicate with other apps.
简短来说这就是它在任何地方都能全屏和非全屏
The short story is that full offscreen and fullscreen are
但是 iOS Web 做不到  应用被埋没在复杂的书签和元标签中
possible everywhere, but with ioS web it's not ideal, hidden in obscure book marking
大多数用户都不知道怎样才能获得这些好处
and meta tags, and that most users don't know enough about to take advantage of.
你可以放到首屏  但它依赖于已经被废弃的 Application Cache 特性
You can do home screen, and it depends on the application cache which has been
它处处都是坑和其它风险
deprecated and, is pretty riddled with traps and dangers.
那么  摄像头和麦克风呢？ 这样就能捕捉视频  并
So then camera and microphone: this is being able to capture
进行实时通话和录像了
video, doing real time calling and recording.
在 Chrome 中  很快就会通过试验性特性提供大量此类支持
In Chrome, there is a lot of support coming soon that is experimental right now, but for
但是对于 iOS Web 还没有关于这些的时间表
ioS web, no time when you are access these things.
还要能检查屏幕方向以及阻止屏幕进入休眠状态。
Being able to check screen orientation and stop the screen from going
to sleep.
iOS Web 不存储这些输入  用户该如何与设备交互？
IOS web doesn't store this -- input, how do users interact with the device?
触控手势、语音识别以及对 Web 来说相对较新的访问剪贴板和指纹识别
Touch gestures, speech recognition, which is
relatively new for web, clipboard access and fingerprint.
对触控的支持无处不在  真棒
Touch support is everywhere,s that's great.
你可以得到触控事件  并且通过库来让它用起来更简单
You can have touch events and use libraries that make those easy to work
with.
关掉指纹识别有时候可能更好  因为它只在 iOS 的 Hybrid 和原生应用中才能用
Fingerprint off is something that is pretty - fingerprint auth is available only on iOS
hybrid native.
我不确定你能否在 Android 上使用它
I'm sure you could work with Android's.
目前还没有现成的插件能支持它
There aren't plugins out the box right now that work with it.
对于它何时能用在 Web 上  也还没有时间表
And no timeline on when those will be availability in the web.
我估计  它是由 iOS 引领的领域
There is one category where iOS leads, I guess.
还要知道设备在哪里  它们什么时候离开或进入某个地点  以及
Knowing where the device is, when they leave and enter a place, and being
能够跟踪设备运动的事件 —— 分别通过重力感应、陀螺仪、传感器
able to track device-motion events on the accelerometer, gyroscope, sensors individually.
位置 —— 能让你知道用户的地理位置
Location - you can know the user's location.
地理位置目前在 Web 上还不可用
Geofencing isn't available on the web.
你可以破解它  或者  只是取得用户的位置  并且检查他们什么时候进入
You can hack it or just pull the user's location and check when they've entered a
某个特定的位置  但是你不能说：“告诉我用户啥时候进入了这个区域”
certain area, but you can't say, "Let me know when the user has got to this area."
这没有原生支持
That's not natively supported.
操作系统：让你能访问
Operating system: so being able to access being able
离线存储、文件系统  还能让你访问联系人、日历等API
to access offline storage, file system, being able to access APIs like contacts and calendar.
离线存储的好处无处不在
Offline storage payments are available everywhere.
Safari 和 Chrome 的实现不一样  但是你可以系统中集成的支付接口
Safari go Chrome have different implementations, but you can pay with
进行支付
your native payments integration.
但无法访问联系人和日历  而且也我也没有看到
And no contact or calendar access, and there is no
任何打算在浏览器中直接支持这些的时间表
timeline or chatter I've seen of being able to work with these things directly.
就像Google自己的应用一样  你可以使用 API  通过它来访问
You could use APIs, like if you're using Google apps,
日历和联系人信息
access the calendar and contact through that.
但还是不理想
Not ideal.
再来看性能
Going to the performance.
我得到了一些新的内容来讲  但不是很深入
I've got a few things to say here, not a whole lot of depth.
每秒60帧  在任何地方都够用了
60 frames per second, is achievable anywhere.
Web 中  你可以通过 Hybrid 和原生来实现
With the web, you can do it with hybrid, native.
原生 UI 可能是最简单的实现方式
Native UI tends to deliver the easiest experience to make this happen.
你们可以推动它们  让它们变得更好
You can leverage them out the box and they tend to be better.
要注意的是   在任何平台上  都很容易写出性能很差的应用
It's worth knowing that a bad performance is just as
easily accomplished on any platform.
如果你是一个开发人员  并且不愿意思考性能的问题
If you as a developer are lazy and not thinking about
你就可能会让任何东西变得很慢  而这种现象我在实践中曾经
performance, you can make something really slow, and I've seen this in practice
观察到很多很多次
too many times to recount.
你必须很能干
You have to be smart.
你必须考虑性能问题
You have to think about performance.
如果你很能干并且投入了足够的精力  那么就能把一切都变快
If you're smart and put in enough effort, you can make anything fast.
我鼓励你们自己深入到这些框架中
I encourage you to look into these frameworks yourself
实际使用它们  感受它们的性能与用户体验  并且
and experience how they feel, how performant they are and the user experience and
感受用户如何看待过渡、动画和交互
how the user perceives the transitions, animations, and interactions.
这些不同的解决方案时开发效率如何？
How effective are you going to be with these different solutions?
关于生产率  我会考虑四件事  你可能也要自己考虑下它们
Four things I would think about with productivity and things that you need to look
看看你的团队如何工作  以及你怎样才能用好这些不同的工具
out on your own, look at how your team works and how well you can play with these
different tools.
可测试性是一大块儿
Testability is a big one.
对Angular本身  我们非常关注这些
At Angular itself, we care a lot about this.
那些工具： Ionic 、 NativeScript 等等
These tools, Ionic, NativeScript, and others in
都会提升可测试性  并且把这些实践内建进去
the system, will leverage testability and built in those lines and this is pretty well
它们在这方面都做得不错
covered by everyone.
拥有一个好的测试用例、Mock和单元测试是很关键的
Having a good testing story, mocking, and unit-testing, is really key.
然后来看社区：社区有多么积极主动？
Then community: how active and engaged is the community?
社区的激励性和吸引力怎么样？
How engaged and excited is the community?
当你在某些事情上陷入困境时  能从社区获得帮助吗？
Are you going to be able to get help when you get stuck on something?
可扩展性如何？
Extensibility?
有没有插件式架构？
Is there a plugin architecture?
在使用某个工具时，一旦陷入困境该怎么办？
A time when I get stuck and won't get out of something using one of these
tools?
以及代码共享：我能在多个应用之间共享多少代码？
And code-sharing: how much code can I share between my application?
使用 Hybrid 方案  你可以共享整个应用的绝大部分代码  只有少数不同
With hybrid, you could share pretty much your whole application with just a few things
here and there.
使用原生 JavaScript 方案  你可以共享服务  或
With native JavaScript or with NativeScript, you could have services
那些能通过纯 JavaScript 方式共享的东西  但这取决于你决定在两者之间共享多少代码
or things that are purely JavaScript-shared, but it's up to you to decide how much you
以及这些共享能给你节省多少时间
can share between the two, and how much that saves you.
我这里讲了很多东西
I covered a lot of stuff.
我可能忘了点什么  可能有些细节错误  但是我从别人那得到了很多帮助
I probably forgot some things, got some details wrong, but I did get a lot of help from people
让我能确信我所说的这些是正确的
to make sure I was representing things correctly.
所以  我还是要鼓励你们在Web开发中自己尝试下 NativeScript 、 Web 和 Ionic
So I would like to encourage you to try Angular 2 for NativeScript web and
Ionic on your own.
取决于开发者的经验
Check out the developer experience.
他们完成了一项伟大的工作：让尝试这些技术变得更简单
They've all done a great job to make it easy to try these things.
评估下这些技术是否和你的目标相匹配
Evaluate how well they meet your goals.
感谢来自 Ionic 和 Google 等团队的伙计们
Thanks to folks from Ionic, and Google, and the help
以及帮助我们收集本幻灯片中的内容的人们  感谢你们的帮助
getting the content together for this slide, and in general, just being helpful.
其它
Otherwise.
这里是与本项目相关的链接
Here are the links to the project.
稍后我会把这些幻灯片发推并共享它们
I will Tweet the slides and share them later.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
[APPLAUSE].